Jacob Nathanson

Web Developer in C

317 6th ave, Brooklyn, NY, 11215

iacobnath93@gmail.com

347.489.2611

Objective

Recent Bootcamp graduate with over 3 years of experience in Education. Patient and resilient problem solver seeking to obtain a challenging position that utilizes current knowledge of web development and design. Positive outlook and team player.

Skills

HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, JavaScript (ES6), React, React Native, Bootstrap, Node, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, git, GitHub, VS Code.

Personal Projects

Dreamy - (live site - github)

A dream journal app built with the MERN stack, allowing users to perform CRUD operations on their journal entries. Uses passport, JSON web-tokens, and Google Oauth to authenticate users.

Banh Mi Mami - (github)

React Native app to order Vietnamese food from a fictional local restaurant. Utilizes Redux Toolkit to control and update menu items, user information, and shopping cart.

NYC Foodies' Trucks - (live site - github)

React single-page application used to explore fictional local food trucks and order catering. Utilizes bootstrap for design and redux toolkit for state management.

Education

- Full-Stack Web & Mobile Development,

- JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures,

Responsive Web Design

- BA Psychology & Music

NuCamp 2021-2022

FreeCodeCamp - 2020

FreeCodeCamp - 2020

University of Michigan - 2011-2015

Other Experiences

Magic Ears/ ESL Teacher

APRIL 2020-DECEMBER 2021, REMOTE

- Conducted 30-minute online English lessons for classes of 1-4 Chinese students per session.
- Consistently ranked above 90% approval from student and parent rankings.

Fisher's SuperKids/ ESL Teacher

AUGUST 2019- MARCH 2020 DA NANG, VIETNAM

- Taught English lessons for Vietnamese students ages 5 18, with classes averaging between 10-15 students.
- Provided weekly video-speaking challenges to review material and produce language in real-world scenarios.
- Used multimedia software and online activities to increase student engagement.

Vietnam USA Society/ ESL Teacher

FEBRUARY 2018-AUGUST 2020 HCMC, VIETNAM

- Taught English lessons for Vietnamese students ages 5 18, with classes averaging between 18-20 students.
- Awarded teacher of the year recognition due to high student performance and satisfaction.